CHRISTINE SCHATZ

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

www.christineschatz.com

**** 323-828-8487

♀ Los Angeles, CA

in /christineschatz

♠ ChristineSchatz

SUMMARY

I truly enjoy problem solving. Whether it's figuring out how an app's data should be structured or how a user experience should be designed, I'm energized by crafting creative solutions to problems. I'm drawn to good people who enjoy sharing ideas and making a difference.

EDUCATION

Northampton Community College

A.S. Computer Science 2015 Dean's List, GPA: 3.9

University of California, San Diego

B.A. Visual Arts: Media 2008 Graduated with Honors

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Ruby, Java, GraphQL FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES: Rails, React, Vue TESTING: RSpec, Capybara, Cypress, Jest FRONT END: HTML5, CSS, Sass, React, Vue METHODOLOGIES: Object-oriented design, Agile

DATABASE: ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, SQL

DEVOPS: Docker, Vagrant

ACTIVITIES

The Loop · Founder & Writer

Music blogger for popular, Hype-Machine ranked music blog "The Loop." I work with PR agents and artists to feature independent music. I'm also a music reviewer for Fluence.io

Coders > Cancer Hackathon · Developer

Collaborated on a team of 4 to develop Ladybug, a text messaging system that reminds women to do their monthly self breast exam. Used Ruby on Rails and HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to design the splash page

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Fender Musical Instruments Corporation

Los Angeles, CA Jan. 2019 - May 2020

- Worked with the data, design, and marketing teams to improve existing applications
- Played a key role on the growth and acquisition squad in delivering new features
- Refactored components to improve code efficiency
- Built pages powered by Gatsby and GraphQL

Software Engineer

Remote Apr. 2017 - Dec. 2018

Penn State University

- Built various ed tech applications using Ruby on Rails, Vue, and Angular
- · Worked with faculty members in the development process, from prototype to deliverable
- · Fixed bugs and improved existing applications

Junior Full Stack Engineer

New York, NY Jan. 2016 - Apr. 2017

- Wrote JavaScript, riot.js, jQuery to implement new front end features on pet retail website, including a store locator
- Used PHP (Laravel) on the backend
- Fixed bugs
- Refactored and cleaned up parts of a large legacy codebase

Junior Developer (Contract)

ValuePenguin

New York, NY Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Built interactive tools such as a credit card calculator using React
- Wrote Scala to customize data on the back end
- Developed in Docker containers

PROJECTS

Emotional Baggage Check iOS app

The iOS app version of the popular desktop site Emotional Baggage Check. Users can post "baggage" anonymously as well as receive an anonymous response.

- Reached phase 2 of a startup accelerator program
- Used Swift and Parse API for the backend
- Utilized MVC design patterns, divide and conquer strategies, and debugging tools throughout development

Stack: Swift, Objective-C, Parse

the <hive>

A social networking site for software developers looking to collaborate on a side project. Users can coordinate meetups using an in-app messaging system. Users can also search for a project by any given city or zip code.

- $\bullet \quad \hbox{Played a large role in implementing the Google Geocoding API to render location results}.$
- Designed the splash page
- Built a portion of the CRUD features for projects
- Implemented AJAX for smoother data loading

Stack: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Materialize, Sass URL: https://code-hive.herokuapp.com

AWARDS

Style of Sound · Best Music Blog Award

Oct. 2014

Awarded ranking in Style of Sound's "Most Influential Music Blogs of 2014" list